

PROFILE

Housekeeping professional with solid experience in development, growth and leadership of personnel in room division.

Detail oriented and organized, able to meet deadlines and excel in multiple assignments, very good in implementing effective systems, strategies and procedures to improve service quality, productivity and performance of the team

Hotel Cleaning Champion and leading the monthly Marriott Commitment to Clean audit.

CONTACT



Abu Dhabi - Mohamed bin Zayed City



+971506123352



Hussein.Khalil@mail.com



24 July 1977



Syria

RESUME

EDUCATION

- BA in Hospitality Management from Bournemouth University - England 2002
- Higher diploma in Hotel Administration from College of Tourism and Hotel Management Cyprus 2001
- Diploma in Front Office Procedures & Housekeeping from Educational Institute of American Hotel and Lodging Industry 2000-2001

EXPERIENCE



2018- Now

Style Manager (Executive housekeeper)

W Abu Dhabi by Marriott – Yas Island (499 rooms)

Area of responsibility (Rooms, Public Area, Laundry & Uniform)

2015-2018

Assistant Executive housekeeper

Yas Viceroy Hotel Abu Dhabi (499 rooms)

Area of responsibilities (Rooms, Public Area, Laundry & Uniform)

2014-2015

Housekeeping Manager

Emirates Palace Hotel- Abu Dhabi (394 rooms)

Area of responsibilities (Rooms, Public Area)

2011-2013

Duty Manager

Emirates Palace Hotel- Abu Dhabi (394 rooms)

2010 -2011

Night Manager

Emirates Palace Hotel- Abu Dhabi (394 rooms)

2007-2010

Assistant Head Concierge

Emirates Palace Hotel- Abu Dhabi (394 rooms)

TRAINING

- Train the trainer
- Transformational leadership
- Quality guest service
- Brand training
- Service recovery (complain handling)
- Time to talk together
- DNA flair management workshop
- Departmental trainer workshop
- GHA discovery workshop
- Fire & safety
- Crises incident management training
- Essential collaboration
- EHSMS awareness training
- Time to talk training
- Connect Quality conversations
- Protocol & Etiquette Training
- Finance for non-finance
- Competency-Based Interviewing Skills
- Foundation of cleaning

OTHER BACKGROUND

- Chosen to be part of "Stronger together" campaign by DCTA in 2020 after the first lockdown.
- Former Les Clefs d'Or member UICH " Golden Keys"
- GHA Discovery Hotel Championhotel loyalty program 2012-2014
- Good Knowledge of handling and dealing with Protocol & Delegations
- Viceroy Leadership award 2016
- Hotel Cleaning Champion

KEY SKILLS Room Division Front Office Preopening



Inventory Management Strategic Operation Planning Interviewing

Housekeeping Preopening

Revenue Analysis

Training **Building High Performance Team** Team Management

Handling Complains Handling Delegations Dealing with Emergencies

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Financial Management & Cost Control



LANGUAGES

